===== PAGE 44 =====
31
Proprietary & Confidential
QLAdmin - Main Menu Policy Display2.  Names Tab  Displays additional coverage and modal premium detail, along withname and address information for the insured, payor, assignee, andbeneficiary. 3.  Agent Tab  Displays commission and override information  by agent for thepolicy.  4.  Memo Tab
 Displays the various memos recorded for the policy and allows foradding, editing and printing memos.5.  User-Defined Tab
 Displays the data stored in a user-defined table which is customized by
the user
.6.  Claims Tab
 Displays all death claim
 and surrender data for a life policy, or health
claim
 data for a health policy.7.  Reinsurance Tab
 Shows how much of a policy is retained and reinsured, the reinsurancecompany, treaty, and the reinsurance billing history.  Only clients thatare using the Reinsurance module will see this tab.8.  Underwriting Tab
 Shows all underwriting information
 on the policy. Users must havethe appropriate security settings
.How can I print a policy summary and status?Locate the desired policy in Policy Display and click the Print button.  The one-page Policy Statusshows summary information about the paid-to and bill-to dates, coverage, insured and owner, agentinformation, NFO and dividend options, premium and premium history, and cash and loan values.Unlike automatic policy status prints, these on-demand status prints are not saved in the policy's
correspondence history
.
37
39 338
43
45
159
48 114
214
51
53 183
485
92

===== PAGE 61 =====
48
⌐ 2026 QLAdmin Solutions QLAdmin Solutions
Policy DisplayQLAdmin - Main Menu
5.1.1.6
Claims TabAll pending and finalized death claims, cash surrenders, or health claim details will be displayed in theClaims Tab.  If a claim is deleted for any reason and the policy is reinstated back to an active status,the claim details will be removed while the previous claim memos will be retained.  
Note:If the policy displayed is a health insurance policy, the Policy Maintenance Claim buttonwill process a  new health claim
, and the Claims Tab will show all health claimhistory.Policy Display - Claims Tab Data Fields(1)  Ph Phase of coverage that was processed.  Zero indicates all phases wereprocessed.(2)  Number Death claim or health claim number.(3)  Status Status of the claim
 or surrender.  (4)  Death Date of death.(5)  Reported Date the death or surrender was reported. (6)  CompletedDate the claim or surrender was completed.(7)  Paid Date the claim or surrender was paid, settled, or denied.(8)  Net Payment Net policy benefit paid including dividends, loans, and/or premiums.(9)  Amount Ins Face amount of the policy.(10)  Dividends Amount of dividends on the policy
.(11)  Ph Phase of coverage that was processed.  Zero indicates all phases wereprocessed.(12)  Disb Benefit disbursement code for the payment (A - ACH, C - Check, E- Escheat,H - Hold).(13)  Check # Check number for benefit.  Check number manually entered, or auto-populated if integrated with accounting.  (14)  Amount Amount of the policy benefit paid. (15)  Name AddressPayee that received benefit.(16)  MemoDeath claim memos.(17)  Memo ActionsAdd, edit, save and print death claim memos.
209
114
134

===== PAGE 87 =====
74
⌐ 2026 QLAdmin Solutions QLAdmin Solutions
Policy DisplayQLAdmin - Main Menu
5.1.2.7
Loan HistoryHow do I view the loan history for a policy?1.Go to the Policy menu and choose either Display by Number or Display by Alpha.  2.Locate and display the desired policy.3.Right-click on any part of the gray area inside the policy display window.4.From this right-click menu select Loan History.The Loan History window will be displayed and shows all loan transactions for the policy. Thisinformation expands on the loan summary
 shown on the Coverage Tab of Policy Display. Loantransactions include loans granted, loan payments, loan interest charged, and automatic premiumloans processed. The transaction type, date, amount and loan balance are displayed. Current loaninformation is shown and includes the accrued interest, the loan balance and the date to which interestis accrued.  The Loan History for a policy can be printed by clicking the Print button.
Policy Right Click - Loan History Data Fields(1)  Transaction Type of loan transaction.(2)  Date Date the transaction.(3)  Amount Amount of the transaction.(4)  Balance Loan balance after the transaction.
32

===== PAGE 88 =====
75
Proprietary & Confidential
QLAdmin - Main Menu Policy Display(5)  Accrued Interest Interest accrued to date.(6)  Current Balance Current loan balance.(7)  Interest Paid ToDate through which interest has been paid.Why is the Policy Display loan balance field highlighted yellow?The policy loan balance field displays the loan balance for the policy, if any. If the loan balance field ishighlighted yellow, this indicates the policy has become overloaned. A policy is overloaned when theloan balance exceeds the cash value, and available dividends/suspense money. Once the policy is nolonger overloaned, or the policy terminates, the highlight will disappear.  Recall that the interest rate on a policy is set in the Plan Information File
 on the general tab, or onthe plan values options
 tab for state-specific loan interest rates.
Which tables are affected?QuikLoan
Policy LoansRelated Topics:Processing Policy Loans
524
533
827
130

===== PAGE 127 =====
114
⌐ 2026 QLAdmin Solutions QLAdmin Solutions
Policy DisplayQLAdmin - Main Menu
5.1.3.2
Processing a Death ClaimHow do I process a death claim?1.Go to the Policy menu and choose either Display by Number or Display by Alpha.  2.Locate and display the desired policy.3.Click on the Policy Maintenance button. The default maintenance date will be the current date,however the Date of Death should be entered when processing a death claim. This date is used incalculating policy financial values.4.Click the Claim button. The Multiple Phases window will be displayed. Supplemental benefits (plan
codes
 starting with 9) must be processed first. Click Yes to process a single phase of coverage.5.Click No to process the entire policy. All phases of coverage with the same client ID as the basecoverage will be included in the claim amount. The remaining phases of coverage will be lapsed.Once the Death Claim window is displayed, follow the steps below to complete the Status, Details andBenefit information. The claim number may already be assigned, depending on the company's settingin System Configuration. All pending and finalized death claim details will be displayed in the ClaimsTab of Policy Display. If the policy displayed is a health insurance policy, the Policy Maintenance Claimbutton will allow health claim adjudication, and the Claims Tab will show all health claim history.      
Note:  Supplemental benefits (plan codes
 starting with 9) must be processed first. Repeatthe claim process to finish processing the other phases of coverage.    Step 1 - Select the StatusThe Death Claim window shows four Status options for processing the death claim: Pending,Paid in Full, Settled or Denied. Choose the appropriate status and enter any notes regardingthe insured or the claim applicant. To save the claim for future processing, keep the claim inPending status.
633
633

===== PAGE 128 =====
115
Proprietary & Confidential
QLAdmin - Main Menu Policy Display PendingDisplays the calculated death benefit net of any financial values andpremium accruals. Pending claims are excluded from billing,automated correspondence and premium posting. The contingentbeneficiary checkbox is disable while the claim is pending. Paid In Full Displays the calculated death benefit net of any financial values andpremium accruals.Settled Allows for manual entry of a lesser Death Benefit amount.  Denied Displays the calculated gross premiums to be refunded on the policy.Check the Do Not Refund Prem checkbox to deny the claim withoutrefunding all premiums paid. Example: an AD&D policy where causeof death was not an accident.Step 2 - Complete the DetailsA Claim Number, Date of Death, Reported Date, and Cause of Death must be entered beforedeath claim processing can continue. The Cause of Death drop down menu contains the top100 causes of death as listed by the ICD-10 table (compiled and copyrighted by the WorldHealth Organization). The list can be customized by clicking the Add Cause of Death button. If the system is configured to assign the claim number
, that field will be populated. Claimdata is calculated through the Maintenance Date entered, which should have been the date ofdeath. Manual adjustments to the benefit should be entered in the Interest/Adjustments field.If the date of death is within two years of the issue date or reinstatement date, the policy iswithin its two-year contestable period, and the Contestable checkbox will be checked. Uncheckthe contestable indicator if needed. The Yes/No contestable indicator will appear on theClaims tab of Policy Display.If the claim being processed is an annuity, the Apply Surr Charges checkbox will be enabled.Surrender charges are deducted from the net benefit. If the annuity is subject to Market ValueAdjustments, the Apply MVA checkbox is enabled.Step 3 - Calculate and Review ValuesClick the Calculate button to update the death benefit data. The Calculate button must beclicked each time the claim window is accessed. The system will account for dividenddeposits, policy loans, and premium refunds or deductions. If paying interest on a death claim,the Interest on Death Claims account
 must be set up. All values will be displayed in theBenefits portion of the Death Claim Window. Click the OK button to finalize the claim and display the Payee window. After the claim isfinalized, the system will print before-and-after policy status pages, including accounting
information
 for the death claim transaction, and the policy status will be updated to 53(Death Claim).Step 4 - Complete the Payee TransactionThe payee window appears for multiple policy benefit disbursement transactions, so theTransaction Description field will show what type of transaction is being processed. If the policyhas primary and/or contingent beneficiaries listed, their information will be populated to thepayee fields. Check the Archive checkbox to save a payee to be inserted on future payments.Click the Insert button to select a previously archived payee.  If the policy has an assignee, the payee window will allocate 100% of the disbursement to the
476
380
630

===== PAGE 143 =====
130
⌐ 2026 QLAdmin Solutions QLAdmin Solutions
Policy DisplayQLAdmin - Main Menu
5.1.3.7
Processing a LoanHow do I process loan transactions on a policy?1.Go to the Policy menu and choose either Display by Number or Display by Alpha.  2.Locate and display the desired policy.  The loan balance field  will be highlighted yellow if thepolicy has become overloaned.3.Click on the Policy Maintenance button and confirm the date for the Loan transaction.  The defaultdate will be the current date.  4.Click the Loan button.  The Loan Maintenance window will be displayed.Note:If a policy has zero cash value, the Loan button cannot be selected, even if the policyhas an outstanding loan. 
The Loan Maintenance window displays all current loan information for the policy, including thecalculated cash value, existing loan data, and the maximum loan amount currently available.  Loaninterest is calculated as either Interest in Advance, or Interest in Arrears, and is calculated from loananniversary to loan anniversary.  The Loan functions allow for borrowing new funds, making payments on existing loans, assigning ascheduled loan payment to be billed, or editing loan values.  The transaction history for all loanpayments can be seen in the right-click menu option Loan History
.  From the four loan options,decide how the policy loan should be processed.   1.  Make LoanAfter clicking the Loan button, the system will calculate the maximum loan amount available.  If thepolicy has no cash value, the system will not allow a policy loan or loan payment to be processed.  If the policy has sufficient cash value, the Loan Maintenance window will appear.  Click the Make Loanbutton, then enter the amount of the loan.  Any premiums due will be added to the loan amount if thepolicy paid-to date is less than the loan date. If the loan interest is payable in advance, the interestcapitalized to the policy anniversary will also be added to the loan amount.  The maximum loan amountwill reflect the amount of interest to accrue for interest payable in arrears.
32
74

===== PAGE 145 =====
132
⌐ 2026 QLAdmin Solutions QLAdmin Solutions
Policy DisplayQLAdmin - Main Menu
4.  Edit LoanThe Edit Loan function is most often used to adjust loan balances that were erroneously converted tothe QLAdmin system.  When editing the loan values, the balance of the current loan and the interestpaid-to date for the loan can be changed.  Any adjustment in the loan balance will be recorded ascapitalized interest on the loan, whether the adjustment is positive or negative.  
How do I enter a loan-payoff payment?When accessing the Loan maintenance feature to view the loan balance and quote a payoff amount,the user must enter a Maintenance Date.  When the loan payoff amount is received from the insured,that same Maintenance Date must be entered to ensure no additional interest is calculated, therebycausing the loan balance to increase.    How do I make a loan for the policy premium only?To create a loan for the amount of the premium due, make a new loan for zero dollars. The premiumdue will be deducted from the new loan amount, and the net effect is a loan for the premium only. How do I reverse a loan payment applied in error?To reverse a loan payment applied in error, make a new loan for the amount that needs to be reversed. Click the Maintenance button at the bottom of policy display, use the same date as the original/incorrect loan payment, then click the Loan button.  See the previous question on making a new loan.How do I reverse a loan granted in error?

===== PAGE 735 =====
722
⌐ 2026 QLAdmin Solutions QLAdmin Solutions
QuikBllh - Billing HistoryQLAdmin Tables 
7.58
QuikBlll - Billing Loan InterestINDEX KEYQuikBlll.ntx SUBSTR(MPOLICY,-1,1) + MBILLFRM + MNOTICEFIELD NAME FIELD TYPE FEILDLENGTH FIELD DESCRIPTION
MPOLICY
CHARACTER
10.0
Policy number
MGROUP
CHARACTER
8.0
Group number
MSTATUS
CHARACTER
2.0
Policy status
MBILLFRM
CHARACTER
1.0
Billing form
MNOTICE
CHARACTER
1.0
Notice type (1 or 2)
MISSDT
DATE
8.0
Policy issue date
MMODE
NUMERIC
2.0
Policy mode
MMOSDUE1
NUMERIC
4.0
Months due - annual
MMODEPREM1
NUMERIC
10.2
Premium due - annual
MMOSDUE2
NUMERIC
4.0
Months due - semi-annual
MMODEPREM2
NUMERIC
10.2
Premium due - semi-annual
MMOSDUE3
NUMERIC
4.0
Months due - quarterly
MMODEPREM3
NUMERIC
10.2
Premium due - quarterly
MMOSDUE4
NUMERIC
4.0
Months due - monthly
MMODEPREM4
NUMERIC
10.2
Premium due - monthly
MLOANBILL
NUMERIC
10.2
Amount billed for policy loan
MDUEDATE
DATE
8.0
Premium due date
MINSNAME
CHARACTER
30.0
Insured name
MACCTNO
CHARACTER
35.0
Billing account number
MOWNNAME
CHARACTER
30.0
Owner name
MOWNADDR1
CHARACTER
50.0
Owner address line 1
MOWNADDR2
CHARACTER
50.0
Owner address line 2
MOWNCSZ
CHARACTER
65.0
Owner city, state, zip code
MPAIDTO
DATE
8.0
Paid to date
MBILLTO
DATE
8.0
Bill to date
MSYSDATE
DATE
8.0
System date
MSTARTDATE
DATE
8.0
First day of billing cycle
MENDDATE
DATE
8.0
Last day of billing cycle
MOWNZIP
CHARACTER
12.0
Owner zip code
MSUSPENSE
NUMERIC
10.2
Suspense balance
MMODEDIV
NUMERIC
10.2
Dividend amount for mode billed
MVALADDR
LOGICAL
1.0
Valid address indicator

===== PAGE 746 =====
733
Proprietary & Confidential
QLAdmin Tables QuikClmp - Death Claim Payee Details
7.67
QuikClms - Death ClaimsINDEX KEYQuikClms.ntx MPOLICY + STR(MPHASE,2,0)FIELD NAME FIELD TYPE FIELDLENGTH FIELD DESCRIPTION
MPOLICY
CHARACTER
10.0
Policy number
MPHASE
NUMERIC
2.0
Phase of coverage
CLAIMNUM
CHARACTER
20.0
Claim number
CLAIMSTAT
NUMERIC
2.0
Claim status (Pending - 1; Paid in Full - 2;Settled- 3; Denied - 4, Matured - 98; Surrenders -99))
DTOFDEATH
DATE
8.0
Date of death
RPTDATE
DATE
8.0
Reported date
PDDATE
DATE
8.0
Paid date
MPAID
NUMERIC
10.2
Amount paid
MFACE
NUMERIC
10.2
Face amount
DIVIDENDS
NUMERIC
10.2
Dividend accumulations
LOAN
NUMERIC
10.2
Loan balance
NETDB
NUMERIC
10.2
Net death benefit
PREMIUM
NUMERIC
10.2
Premium accrual
SUSPENSE
NUMERIC
10.2
Suspense refunded
ADJUST
NUMERIC
10.2
Manual adjustment
CAUSE
CHARACTER
3.0
ICD-1- cause of death
MEMOTEXT
MEMO
10.0
Claim memo
ORIGSTATUS
CHARACTER
2.0
Original status
ACCPTDATE
DATE
8.0
Completed date
MCONTEST
LOGICAL
1.0
Contestable claim indicator
MINTST
CHARACTER
2.0
State where interest is applicable
MINTDAYS
NUMERIC
5.0
Days to earn interest
MINTRATE
NUMERIC
8.4
Interest rate
MINTAMT
NUMERIC
10.2
Amount of interest earned
MSURRCHG
LOGICAL
1.0
Surrender charge
MSEQ
NUMERIC
3.0
Order of benefit payments
MHOLDINT
NUMERIC
12.2
Interest earned on held payment
MFEDTAX
NUMERIC
12.2
Federal tax withheld

===== PAGE 747 =====
734
⌐ 2026 QLAdmin Solutions QLAdmin Solutions
QuikClms - Death ClaimsQLAdmin Tables MSTTAX NUMERIC 12.2 State tax withheldMCLMPNDLTR NUMERIC 3.0 Pending claim notice number of daysMFACPMT LOGICAL 1.0 MedSupp - facility payment codeMPHPAIDTO DATE 8.0 Phase of coverage paid-to date

===== PAGE 748 =====
735
Proprietary & Confidential
QLAdmin Tables QuikClms - Death Claims
7.68
QuikClnt - Client Information MasterINDEX KEYQuikClnt.ntx MCLIENTIDQuikClnm.ntx PadR(RTrim(Upper(MLNAME)) +", "+ RTrim(Upper(MFNAME)) +" "+RTrim(Upper(MMNAME)),60," ")QuikClad.ntx UPPER(MADDR1)QuikCltx.ntx MTAXID + MTYPEQuikCldb.ntx DToS(MDOB)QuikClmb.ntx PADR(LTRIM(MMEMBERID),14," ")QuikClmbi.ntxPADR(LTRIM(MMSMBI),11," ")
FIELD NAME
FIELD TYPE
FIELDLENGTH
FIELD DESCRIPTION
MCLIENTID
CHARACTER
12.0
Client ID
MTYPE
CHARACTER
1.0
Client type (I- insured, A- agent, B- bank)
MTAXID
CHARACTER
9.0
Tax ID
MTAXIDTYPE
CHARACTER
1.0
Tax ID type (S- SSN, E-EID)
MTITLE
CHARACTER
10.0
Name prefix
MFNAME
CHARACTER
20.0
First name
MMNAME
CHARACTER
20.0
Middle name
MLNAME
CHARACTER
30.0
Last name
MSUFFIX
CHARACTER
3.0
Name suffix
MADDR1
CHARACTER
50.0
Address line 1
MADDR2
CHARACTER
50.0
Address line 2
MCITY
CHARACTER
50.0
City
MSTATE
CHARACTER
2.0
State
MZIP
CHARACTER
5.0
Zip code
MZIP2
CHARACTER
4.0
Zip code +4
MCOUNTRY
CHARACTER
4.0
Country code
MPHONEHOME
CHARACTER
10.0
Home phone
MPHONEOFC
CHARACTER
10.0
Office phone
MPHOFCEXT
CHARACTER
5.0
Office phone extension
MPHONECELL
CHARACTER
10.0
Cell phone
MPHONEFAX
CHARACTER
10.0
Fax number
MEMAIL
CHARACTER
128.0
Email address
MDOB
DATE
8.0
Date of birth

===== PAGE 749 =====
736
⌐ 2026 QLAdmin Solutions QLAdmin Solutions
QuikClnt - Client Information MasterQLAdmin Tables MSEX CHARACTER 1.0 SexMMEMBERID CHARACTER 14.0 Company defined member IDMLANGUAGE CHARACTER 1.0 Language (E- English, S- Spanish, F-French)
MPDFPSSWD
CHARACTER
12.0
Password to protect PDF files
MEMAILCORR
LOGICAL
1.0
Recieve correspondence via email
MVALID
LOGICAL
1.0
Invalid address indicator
MDNC
LOGICAL
1.0
Marketing contact opt out indicator
MOFAC
LOGICAL
1.0
OFAC confirmation
MMEMBERDT
DATE
8.0
Member effective date
MMSMBI
CHARACTER
11.0
Medicare Supplement Medicare beneficiaryidentifier number
MFOREIGN
LOGICAL
1.0
Foreign address indicator
MOCCODE
CHARACTER
7
Occupation codes in user-maintained inQuikOcup

===== PAGE 840 =====
827
Proprietary & Confidential
QLAdmin Tables QuikList - Group Bill Information
7.150
QuikLoan - Policy LoansINDEX KEYQuikLoan.ntx MPOLICYFIELD NAME FIELD TYPE FIELDLENGTH FIELD DESCRIPTION
MPOLICY
CHARACTER
10.0
Policy number
MLOANPRIN
NUMERIC
10.2
Loan principal
MLOANBAL
NUMERIC
10.2
Loan balance
MLOANINT
NUMERIC
5.2
Loan interest rate
MLOANINTX
CHARACTER
1.0
Loan interest type (A- advance, R- arrears)
MLOANIDT
DATE
8.0
Interest paid to date
MLOANDATE
DATE
8.0
Loan balance date
MLOANACCR
NUMERIC
10.2
Accrued interest
MLOANBILL
NUMERIC
10.2
Billing loan payment

===== PAGE 841 =====
828
⌐ 2026 QLAdmin Solutions QLAdmin Solutions
QuikLoan - Policy LoansQLAdmin Tables 
7.151
QuikMemo - Policy MemosINDEX KEYQuikMemo.ntxMEMOKEYFIELD NAME FIELD TYPE FIELDLENGTH FIELD DESCRIPTION
MEMOKEY
CHARACTER
10.0
Policy number
MEMOTEXT
MEMO
10.0
Policy memo

